hey everybody okay so I've been doing
these walking talks on Instagram where
we don't have quite as many people so I
didn't know what would happen if we
tried it over here on YouTube and then
we also have a restreaming thing that we
could do but what I wanted to do is I
wanted to talk to you guys about what's
going on right now from my perspective
in terms of how we're seeing this how
we're failing to see this and what we
should be doing about it now the first
thing is is that you've got some super
complicated situation here we've got
riots we got protests we've got people
being peaceful we have people being
violent
we have people being politically
exploited if we have people being naive
we have people overstepping their power
we are both calling for the police to
protect us and calling the police our so
we've got an incredibly complicated
situation which I've tried to talk to
you guys before about in terms of super
position i think ben shapiro recently
made the comment which is it that you
want us to trust a only law enforcement
to have firearms or you don't trust law
enforcement to save your life and this
is exactly the kind of weird false
dichotomy in some sense you know it's
both of course we and then we want our
right to defend ourselves and we don't
want the right of somebody else to gun
down our children so of course in any
kind of a situation where you have a
tremendous number of super positions we
get into these things about people
saying well i think this is about race
and if you don't see this as just being
about race then you're not you're not
getting it or this has nothing to do
with it race it just has to do with the
economy and if people weren't out of
work from Cova you wouldn't be seeing
this or somebody else will say I think
it's because facial our you know our
faces are obscured by masks which is
giving us a sense of anonymity and so
now the public square looks like the
Internet because we can hi
behind a mask and nobody can know who we
are but what I wanted to say about all
this
is that if you're trying not to reduce
this to some simple thing you're going
to be angering everybody who is trying
to reduce this to some very simple thing
and as a result you have to understand
where the portal and our group of people
is coming from which is the fight
against complacency but also against
simplification and when you think back
to Yeats talking about the best or full
of passion of sorry the worst are full
of passionate intensity in the best lack
all conviction I don't know that that's
true or that's false but one of the
reasons that a lot of people lack all
conviction is that they see the
complexity and people want to know is it
still okay to be out in California
actually I was hoping to see whether or
not I could take any of your questions
and whether I could get any of you guys
to come on with me I don't know whether
this is set up for that so in any event
I'm learning the various I'm learning
the various different platforms I cannot
figure out how to get any of you into
chat which is what I was hoping to do so
I might learn this a little bit better
and try it next time but let me at least
leave you all if you can figure out a
way to see how you can join the chat
please do and I'll try to take you but
if I can't figure out how to set it up
for that I will come back next time and
do that there is a thought that I want
to sort of leave which is three years
ago we saw the situation at Evergreen
College Evergreen State College in
Evergreen State College wasn't
processable by most of us if you look at
the videos there was like an amazing
compilation called something like a
student takeover of Evergreen State
College that probably has over a million
views
and you see a lot of these weird issues
cropping up where I think one of the
things is really interesting is that and
and Brett my brother said this pretty
well at the time he said there are two
groups one group wants to end depression
one group wants to reverse oppression I
thought that was fascinating the idea
that reversing oppression means you undo
the stain of humiliation by oppressing
your oppressor and establishing that you
are not to be pushed around so you know
like a weird example of this would be
the Yom Kippur War in Israel in 1973 may
have been necessary for Egypt to
communicate to Israel that it was strong
enough to make peace which Bagan and
Sadat did which passed Sadat his life
and he was assassinated at the parade
grounds and you know there's sort of a
rule in the Middle East which says you
can't make peace unless you do it from a
position of strength and you can't get
strength with that blood on your hands
and so in part one of the things that
may be happening is that you may have
one group that wants to reverse
oppression you have another group that
is you know deeply studied non-violence
the power of the peaceable assembly and
you've got a superposition of these plus
you've got you know effectively white
anarchist agitators who are also part of
this thing and I I'll be honest with you
I think that very little of this has to
do with anything specific to the u.s. I
looked back and I got like a lot of old
tweets and old comments stating what I
thought which is that this is a
worldwide low-grade revolution of a
previously unknown time type I called it
the N squared for no name revolution and
what I said at the time was it hasn't
gotten physical and violent yet it's
violence on the Internet cancel culture
is like killing your digital persona or
it might be killing your work persona
but hasn't actually escalated yet too
much into you know now we're seeing more
businesses that may be being killed off
and never come back and it may escalate
further into wide loss of life what I
what I do
say about that though is that this has
been foreseeable and we've seen it in
Chile we've seen it in Hong Kong we've
seen it in the Netherlands we've seen it
in the holy city of Rome in Iran this is
a worldwide phenomenon and you know we
have a particular instance of it and the
catalyst matters and it doesn't matter
what happened to George Floyd in very
particular way but if you see it in
context you can see that it's very clear
that this is part of something much
larger and I think I'm going to be
talking about that more I'm gonna try to
figure out how to do these live YouTube
streams and I would love to get you guys
in on it please go over to probably Eric
our Weinstein on Instagram that's Eric
our Weinstein where I've been doing this
a lot and if you'll subscribe to me over
there you can get notified when I do the
walk and talk and I've been successfully
integrating about four people during my
10,000 steps a day walk so um great to
see you all thanks for being out here
stay tough stay angry stay optimistic
stay constructive stay focused and above
all stay safe so that we can do this
again and I love you all and thanks for
hanging in there with me my friends be
well